# **JAVIER RAMIREZ**

Software Engineer

J	00	0033770407936							





https://javier-ramirez-leiva.github.io/



Software engineer, lover of its work and willing to make a difference. I have an international experience in countries such as France and Spain as well as in different domains such as CAD, automotive industry, security and IoT. Currently working for Dassault Systemes in Lyon, France.

# **EXPERIENCE**

### **Dassault Systemes / Software Engineer**

08/2019-Present

Electrical System Design app inside the CATIA portfolio of the 3DExperience platform from Dassault Systemes.

- C++ development for CAD and PLM applications to design electrical systems on Windows and Linux OS
- CI/CD management. Tools development on python and bash to improve process
- Development of UI elements based on web technologies
- Draft of technical software specifications and unit testing planning
- Software architecture design focused on re-usability and modules/frameworks
- Model definition for MBSE engineering

#### **Continental** / Software Engineer

01/2017-08/2019

AKKA Technologies on behalf of Continental Automotive France SAS. ECU software development to control a Direct Injection Engine inside the new E-Power technology for Nissan.

- Design of the system architecture for a real-time application. Focus on software reliability
- Software development on C/C++ code conforming the AUTOSAR standard
- Scripting (python and perl) to create automatic tests for validation and non-regression
- Team management, AKKA for Continental. Technical orientation and support of other employees
- Creation of software tools to help with task tracking and planning

## **Rockwell Collins / Software Engineering Intern**

03/2016-09/2016

Security application to control cameras using the detections made by the radar FMWC PSR-500

- C++ development using the QT framework for Windows and Linux OS
- Planning and specification of validation tests
- Software mock-ups for customer demos

#### EDUCATION

### Master of Engineering. Electrical and Electronic engineering

ENSEEIHT (Ecole Nationale Supérieure d'Electrotechnique, d'Informatique, d'Hydraulique et des Télécommunications) 2015 - 2016

## Master of Engineering. Electrical and Electronic engineering

UPNA (Universidad Publica de Navarra) 2014 - 2015

## **Engineering degree. Electronic engineering**

Universidad de La Rioja

# SKILLS

<b>Programming Languages</b>	<b>Software Applications</b>	Technologies	Development Methods
C, C++ (C++ 11)	Visual Studio, QT IDE, Eclipse	Embedded systems	V Cycle, Agile
Python (3.0), Bash, Perl, VBS	Git, CMake, JIRA	CAD, MBSE	Object Oriented Programming, design Patterns, TDD
HTML, Javascript, CSS	CATIA, 3D Experience, Matlab	Real-Time, Multicore, AUTOSAR	CI/CD, Unit Testing, Automatic Testing

# LANGUAGES

Spanish(Native)

• English(Full professional proficienty)

French(Full professional proficienty)